Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Mollie Goldstein, Nov 7, 1981; cuid1303
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd M. Goldstein 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 106 A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Nina Goldstein, Mar 19, 1980; cuid1304
    Interview documents Goldstein's early life in Russia and Canada, her work and political life in Brownsville and East Flatbush, Brooklyn during the 1920s-1930s, and the activities of the Communist Party. The interview also covers the Morgen Freiheit, the International Workers Order, Russian War Relief and aid to Israel during the 1940s, and the Jewish cultural movement in Miami Beach.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd N. Goldstein 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 107 A-D)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Walter Goldwater, Feb 15, 1983; cuid1305
    Goldwater discusses C.L.R. James during the 1920s-1960s, the Workers Party during the 1940s, Trotskyism, anti-Stalinism, neo-conservatism, Pan-Africanism, and Eric Williams.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Goldwater 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 108 A-B)
  - Helen Goodman, Oct 20, 2002; cuid1306
    Interview includes discussions of childhood in Brooklyn and early jobs, the Great Depression, and work in defense plants during World War II. Activity in the UE Local 1707, American Labor Party, and Jewish Association Services for the Aged are discussed, as are May Day parades and her father's socialist activities. The interview also includes comments on the Paul Robeson concert at Peekskill and Rosenberg executions. Goodman also talks about members of her family and working with the Jewish Association Services for the Aged.
    Interview by Laura Helton.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Goodman 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 108A)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Michael Gordon, Mar 25, 1977; cuid1307
    Gordon describes his association with Frontier Films, and coming to film through a background with the Film and Photo League and Group Theatre during the 1930s. Gordon discusses and contrasts the politics of Frontier Films and Group Theatre. Interview also includes discussion of Gordon's work on various projects and associates in Hollywood and New York City.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Gordon 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 109)
  - Grandma Was an Activist, 1983; cuid1308
    Ruth F. Prago, a member of the Oral History of the American Left staff, developed the idea for a radio series based on interviews to be conducted for the OHAL collection. Together with Pacifica Radio, OHAL received a one-year grant from the New York Council for the Humanities to conduct interviews with twenty-five women about radicalism during the 1930s. Radio producers Beth Friend and Charles Potter used these interviews to make a six-part radio series titled "Grandma Was an Activist," first broadcast in 1983. One of the series interviewers, Bea Lemisch, and three of the women interviewed for the series, participated in a panel discussion at the 1984 Berkshire Conference on Women's History.
    The six half-hour segements of "Grandma was an Activist" include excerpts from OHAL interviews with Louise Thompson, Jane Dudley, Alice Dodge Wolfson, Meridel LeSueur, among others.
    1) The Black and the Red 2) How Do You Spell Relief? 3) On the Line 4) They Shall Not Pass 5) Readin' and Ritin' on the Road to Power 6) Militant Muse
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Grandma was an Activist 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 110 A-C)
  - Leah Dillon Grant, Jul 24, 1983; cuid1309
    Interview documents Yiddish literary milieu in 1920s and role of interviewee's uncle, A.M. Dillon. Also covered are the Johnson-Forest Tendency, its leaders and activities during the 1940s, and cultural perspectives.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Grant 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 111)
  - Janet Green, May 29, 2009; cuid1310
    Interview regarding Green's experiences growing up in the Bronx and working in New York City.
    Interview by Jeff Eichler.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Green 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette Green 1)
  - Samuel Greenberg, Oct 27, 1982; cuid1311
    Interview documents the activities of the Yiddish Left in Los Angeles and nationally from the 1930s-1980s. This includes Greenberg's analysis of various personalities in Yiddish literature including Leivick, Avrom Reyzen, Moshe Nadir, and others. He comments on the relative literary merits of the Morgen Freiheit, Forward, and Freie Arbeiter Stimme, and describes the break between the Freiheit and many writers on the Yiddish literary scene.
    Greenberg expresses pessimism regarding Yiddish culture and working class political movements in the 1980s, and details his own loss of faith in the Soviet Union during the preceding decades. Facets of this discussion include the diminished state of Yiddish culture in the Soviet Union, contrasts between his travels there during 1930s and 1980s, and Greenberg's analyses of the reasons for the decline of Jewish progressive movement.
    Duration: 80 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Greenberg 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 112 A-B)
  - Guardian Forum, May 26, 1973; cuid1312
    "What Road to Building a New Communist Party?"; criticism of 1960s politics; history of class struggle.
    Topics included: women's role in class struggle, role of race and nationality in class struggle, discussion of how new Communist Party would be organized, the tension between unity and sects, the activities of the October League
    Hosted by the Guardian newspaper
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Guardian Forum 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 113 A-B)
  - Sarah Gudelman, Nov 3, 1979; cuid1313
    Interview includes discussion of Sarah Gudelman's youth in Russia and Germany, her family history, immigration to Lower East Side in New York City and work in the garment trade. Other topics include life with her husband, the sculptor Gudelman, and the death of their first child. Also discussed are Sarah Gudelman's work as administrator for 18 progressive shuls in Bronx, her assessments of artists and Yiddish literary figures including Moshe Nadir and Itche Goldberg, and her involvement in the Communist Party.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Gudelman 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 396 A-C)
  - Oive Halonen, Feb 27, 1978; cuid1314
    Halonen discusses Finnish-American radicalism in Minnesota and Oregon during the 1910s-1930s, participation in Spanish Civil War as member of Abraham Lincoln Brigade, and experiences as Seattle machinist during the 1940s-1960s.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Halonen 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 114)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Michael Hanusiak, Mar 30, 1983; cuid1315
    Topics covered by this interview include the Ukrainian-American Left, the International Workers Order during the 1930s-1940s, the effects of McCarthyism, problems of organization, publications, and the generational continuity in the ethnic progressive movement through the 1980s.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Hanusiak 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 115)
  - Louis Harap, Mar 19, 1978; cuid1316
    Harap discusses Harvard University during the 1930s, Jewish Survey during the 1940s, Jewish Life during the 1940s-1950s, the Rosenberg case, and Jewish Currents during the 1950s-1970s.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Harap 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 116 A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Harlem Riots Inquiry, Apr 14, 1965; cuid1317
    Interview with Sanford Katz, the attorney representing defendants from the Progressive Labor Movement who were charged with involvement in the Harlem Riots of 1964. Subjects include criticism of actions of grand jury, selection of the grand jury, and the implications of holding Eleanor Goldstein in contempt multiple times over the same questions.
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Harlem Riots Inquiry 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 386)
  - Michael Harrington, Oct 6, 1969; cuid1318
    Interview covers the "prehistory" of Students for a Democratic Society during the late 1950s and the activities of SDS during the 1960s.
    Duration: 109 minutes
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Harrington 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 117)
  - Michael Harrington, May 2, 1988; cuid1319
    Duration: 190 minutes in three parts
    - Access Copy (Box 17, Cd Harrington 3-5)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 117.5 A-C)
  - Daniel Heartquist, Feb 5, 1981; cuid1320
    Interview covers the Socialist movement in Sweden, Swedish-American Socialism, the Left in New England during the 1930s-1940s, and reflections on American Communism.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Heartquist 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 118 A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - James B. Henry -- Transcript, May 11, 1976; cuid1321 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Interview documents the legal prosecution of the International Workers Order in New York State during the 1950s and Henry's role as ex-Special Assistant Attorney General.
    Interview by Howard Brown.
  - Michael Henry, Jun 4, 1980; cuid1322
    Duration: 82 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd M. Henry 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 119 A-B)
  - Philip Hochstein, Oct 28, 1986; cuid1323
    Interview includes discussion of immigration from Russian Empire, youth in Bayonne, New Jersey, and the press and the Left.
    Interview by Diana Maull.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Hochstein 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 424)
  - Otis Hood, Mar 24, 1981; cuid1324
    Interview includes discussion of Hood's union-family background, the New England Left in the 1930s, the Communist Party in Vermont during the 1930s, the Communist Party in Boston during the 1930s-1940s, Hood's experience in prison, and other reflections.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Hood 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 120 A-B)
  - Walter Hoops, Oct 6, 1984; cuid1325
    Interview documents the Saint Louis Free Thought movement from the nineteenth century to 1940s, Hoops' background in Germany, his immigration to the United States, the Rand School of Social Science, the Socialist Party in Saint Louis during the 1930s, and Free Thought and atheism in Saint Louis from the 1940s-1980s.
    Duration: 73 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Hoops 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 121 A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Frank Horzen, Oct 26, 1982; cuid1326
    Interview consists of an analysis of politics in Fontana, California by member of the religious (anti-socialist) South Slav benefit association and steel worker, who later became mayor of Fontana. Also covers are attitudes toward Henry Kaiser and later (Third World) immigrants.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Horzen 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 122)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - International Labor Defense, Jun 21, 1982; cuid1327
    Interview with David Freedman, Sam Neuberger, and Fay Pasternak on International Labor Defense, National Lawyers Guild, and radical legal work in the 1930s-1940s. Interview includes recollections of Joe Brodsky, Carol King, Vito Marcantonio, and others.
    Interview by Ann Ginger and Debra Bernhardt.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILD 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 124 A-C)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 1, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1328
    Interview by David Gurowsky.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 6)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 A)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 1, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1329
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 1.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 1)
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 6)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 A)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 B)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 2, Feb 10, 1975; cuid1330
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 7)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 C)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 2, Dec 16, 1974; cuid1331
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 2.
    The narrator discusses work in the garment industry and figures in the ILGWU during the 1910s-1940s.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 2)
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 8)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 D)
    - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 123 E)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Man 3, Oct 24, 1974
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 3.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 3)
    - Access Copy (Box 1, Cd ILGWU 9)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 G)
    - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 123 F)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 3, Oct 23, 1974; cuid1332
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 3.
    Duration: 60 minutes
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 F)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 4, Nov 19, 1974; cuid1333
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 2.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 E)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 5, Dec 27, 1974; cuid1334
    Interview is on track 1 of CD ILGWU 4.
    Duration: 23 minutes
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 4)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 H)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 6, Oct 22, 1974; cuid1335
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 1.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 B)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 7, Mar 12, 1975; cuid1336
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 5)
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 10)
    - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 123 I)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 J)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Anonymous Woman 8, Jan 2, 1975; cuid1337
    Interview is on track 2 of CD ILGWU 4.
    - Access Copy -- Interview (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 4)
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd ILGWU 8)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 123 D)
    - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 123 H)
  - Evelyn Irsay, Jun 1982; cuid1338
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Irsay 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 383)
  - CLR James, Feb 25, 1974; cuid1339
    Recording of a speech titled "Africa and World Politics" at the University of Rhode Island.
    Recorded by Paul Buhle.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd James 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 81, Audiocassette 369)
  - CLR James, Oct 15, 1981; cuid1340
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd James 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 81, Audiocassette 369)
  - Abdeen Jabara, Mar 28, 1983; cuid1341
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Jabara 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 125 B-C)
  - Jewish People's Chorus, Apr 14, 1980; cuid1342
    Excerpt from performance at Yablon Center in Los Angeles, California.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Jewish People's Chorus 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 126)
  - S.J. Jokubka, Jul 28, 1983; cuid1343
    Interview covers Jokubka's background in Lithuania and activities in Argentina during the 1930s. He also speaks of his editorship of Vilnis, a Chicago-based Lithuanian-language newspaper, since 1942. Jokubka also discusses the problems of publishing ethnic newspaper and the role of cultural activities in the Lituanian-American movement.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Jokubka 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 125 A)
  - Howard Johnson, Oct 17, 1979; cuid1344
    Interview covers Johnson's involvement in show business in Harlem during the 1930s and dancing at the Cotton Club. He also describes his politicization, his entry into the Communist party, community involvement during the 1940s, and figures such as Jackie Robinson and Paul Robeson. Johnson also analyzes the relations of blacks and whites in the Communist Party. The recording also includes a sound reel from his night class.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Johnson 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 127)
  - Howard "Stretch" Johnson, Jun 26, 1984 - Aug 23, 1984; cuid1345
    Interview by Dan Cohen.
    Duration: 330 minutes in five parts; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Johnson 2-8)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 333 A-E)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Howard Johnson -- Transcript, Dec 1990; cuid1346 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    This interview is a part of the series "Oral Histories of African Americans" by the Center for Oral History at the University of Hawaii at Manoa. The interview covers his activities as a performer at the Cotton Club, as a Communist Party organizer, and as an educator.
    Interview by Kathryn Takara.
  - Onni Kaartinen, Jul 7, 1984; cuid1347
    Kaartinen discusses his Finnish-American radical background during the 1930s, the Spanish Civil War, and fraternal and political activities from the 1940s-1970s.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Kaartinen 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 128 A-B)
  - Morris (Moshe) Kaplan, April 15, 1980; cuid1348
    Kaplan discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Kaplan 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 129)
  - Maude White Katz, Oct 18, 1981; cuid1349
    Interview covers Katz's early days in the Communist Party, the fight against white chauvinism, and the Needle Trades Industrial Union's activities during the 1920s.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Katz 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 130)
  - Ed Kempf, Oct 29, 1978; cuid1350
    Kempf discusses his role as New Jersey Regional Director of the Steel Workers Organizing Committee-Harrison-Hoboken-Jersey City, Crucible Steel, Otis Elevator, the Socialist Party, and the Socialist Workers Party during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 18, Cd Kempf 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 131)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Aaron Kertman, Apr 7, 1980; cuid1351
    Kertman discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kertman 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 132)
  - Anton Kerzic, Jul 27, 1983; cuid1352
    Interview covers the origins of Slovenian-American fraternal movement in Waukegan and North Chicago, Illinois. Kerzic also covers his work in a cooperative grocery store during the 1930s-1940s and work with Finnish-American fraternal group in milk coop during the 1930s-1950s. Kerzic also discusses conflict between the midwestern and eastern factions of the SNPJ (Slovenska Narodna Podporna Jednota) and his role as founder of a savings and loan bank in Waukegan.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kerzic 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 133 A-B)
  - Maurice Kish, Sep 23, 1979; cuid1353
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kish 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 397 A-B)
  - Maurice Kish, Oct 29, 1979; cuid1354
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kish 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 398)
  - Maurice Kish, Feb 17, 1983; cuid1355
    Brief interview with Russian-born painter about his family and his work.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kish 4)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 134)
  - Camp Kinderland Reunion, Jun 9, 1979; cuid1356
    Recording includes reminiscences, reading of letters, and songs and dances.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Camp Kinderland 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 135 A-B)
  - Mary Kolehmainen, Mar 10, 1981; cuid1357
    Koloehmainen discusses emigration from Finland, the activities of the Socialist Party, and the Finnish women's newspaper.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kolehmainen 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 136)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Mary Kolehmainen, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1358
    Kolehmainen discusses her immigration to America, life in the Finnish-American Left, the activities of Finns in Boston area during the 1930s-1940s, her role as editor of women's weekly Naisten Viiri, and the support of Finnish-American movement.
    Duration: 35 minutes
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kolehmainen 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 137)
  - Joseph Korn, Apr 16, 1980; cuid1359
    Korn discusses the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF) and the Jewish cultural movement in Los Angeles.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Korn 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 138)
  - Ernest Koski, Jul 31, 1983; cuid1360
    Koski discusses the Finnish-American Left in Mesabi Iron Range and the radical Finnish newspaper Tyomies.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Koski 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 139 A-B)
  - Nettie Kravitz, Apr 1, 1983; cuid1361
    Kravitz discusses the Johnson-Forest Tendency, radical feminism, and activities on the East Coast and in Detroit, from the 1940s-1960s.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kravitz 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 140 A-B)
  - Rose Kryzak, Jan 4, 1982; cuid1362
    Kryzak describes growing up in New York City, her life as a Communist Party member from 1933, her trip to Soviet Union and impressions of it, the Communist Party and women's issues, and the McCarthy period.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Kryzak 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 141)
    - Transcript (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Jacob Kunin -- Transcript, Mar 2, 1967; cuid1363 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    Kunin discusses ethnic groups and politics in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1920s-1940s.
  - Kay Lahusen, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1364
    Interview with Kay Lahusen (also known as Kay Tobin) covers relationship between gay liberation movement and the Left, publications, and legislative campaigns during the 1950s-1970s.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Lahusen 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 143 A-B)
  - Lang, M.P.G. -- Access Copy (Box 10, Cd Lang 1-2)
    Discs are blank.
  - Ollie Leeds, Aug 9, 1983; cuid1365
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Leeds 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 81, Audiocassette 370 A-C)
  - Meridel LeSueur, May 1, 1982; cuid1366
    Interview details author Meridel LeSueur's recollections of Minnesota radicalism during the Great Depression.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd LeSueur 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 144)
  - Aaron Levenstein, Mar 5, 1974; cuid1367
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Levenstein 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 336.5)
  - Alfred Baker Lewis -- Transcript, Sep 8, 1967; cuid1368 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    Lewis and his wife discuss the Socialist Party and the New England region during the 1910s-1940s and the civil rights movement during the 1940s-1960s.
  - Fred Lilja, Jun 28, 1983; cuid1369
    Lilja discusses his immigration to the United States and his work as itinerant miner, lumber worker, and fisherman during the 1910s. He also covers the activities of Finnish-American Left in Monessan, Pennsylvania during the 1920s-1950.
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Lilja 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 146)
  - Sam Liptzin, Mar 22, 1979; cuid1370
    - Access Copy (Box 19, Cd Liptzin 1)